Farrel Company Records 1989.0053
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series IX: Audio Visual Records, 1850-1968
  - Subseries D: Plans and Blueprints
    - Facilities
      - Headgates for the Seymour Dam, 1886 (Box 226:, Folder 1234)
      - Proposed Derby plant, 1952 (Box 226:, Folder 1235-1237)
    - Projects and Equipment
      - Beacon Falls Mill and Power Co. project, 1898 (Box 226:, Folder 1238-1239)
      - Calendar drawing, 1869 (Box 226:, Folder 1240)
      - J.P. Collins and Co. - unidentified, 1883 (Box 226:, Folder 1241)
      - Drawings, [1850s] (Box 226:, Folder 1242)
      - Gun machine, 1918 (Box 226:, Folder 1243)
      - Mud elimination process, 1926 (Box 226:, Folder 1244)
      - Templates and sketches used in making woodentooth mortised gears, 1911 (Box 226:, Folder 1245-1246)
      - Water wheel, 1873 (Box 226:, Folder 1247)
      - Water wheel parts, 1948 (Box 226:, Folder 1248)
- Series X: Historical Papers, 1847-1984
  - Farrel Company
    - Ansonia history (Box 227:, Folder 1249)
    - Company
      - History (Box 227:, Folder 1250)
      - Historical notes (Box 227:, Folder 1251)
      - Printed items (Box 227:, Folder 1252)
    - Farrel, Franklin Sr.: notes and printed items (Box 227:, Folder 1253)
    - Farrel, Franklin Jr.: notes and printed items (Box 227:, Folder 1254)
    - Farrel, Franklin Jr.: Yale Commencement, 1903 (Box 227:, Folder 1255)
    - Farrel, Franklin 3rd, 1945-1972 (Box 227:, Folder 1256-1263)
    - History of Farrel stock (Box 227:, Folder 1264)
    - Industries related to Farrel (Box 227:, Folder 1265-1266)
    - Joy, Franklin: address to Derby Historical Society, 1984 (Box 227:, Folder 1267)
    - Local town history (Box 227:, Folder 1268-1269)
    - Pomini address: history of company (Box 227:, Folder 1270)
    - Pool/Farrel letters, 1868-1872 (Box 227:, Folder 1271)
    - Transcript: patent application of W. Porter and H. Jackson, 1871 (Box 227:, Folder 1272)
    - World's Colombian Exposition, 1893 (Box 227:, Folder 1273)
  - Family Papers
    - Bills and receipts, 1882-1884 (Box 227:, Folder 1274)
    - Family biographical notes (Box 227:, Folder 1275)
    - Family death notices (Box 227:, Folder 1276)
    - Family genealogy, 1955 (Box 227:, Folder 1277)
    - Family legal records, 1881 (Box 227:, Folder 1278)
    - Farrel, Franklin Sr.: condolence letters, 1912 (Box 227:, Folder 1279)
    - Farrel, Franklin Jr.: correspondence, 1916-1917, 1953, 1964 (Box 227:, Folder 1280)
    - Legal papers, 1869, 1877 (Box 227:, Folder 1281)
    - Lissberger stock papers, 1882 (Box 227:, Folder 1282)
    - Newsclipping of Almon Farrel home, 1969 (Box 227:, Folder 1283)
    - Warranty deed to Almon Farrel from Anson Phelps, 1847 (Box 227:, Folder 1284)
  - Reference
    - Banbury, The Master Mixer, 1962 (Box 227:, Folder 1285)
    - Book excerpts, 1898-1938 (Box 227:, Folder 1286)
    - The Great Industries of the United States, 1872 (Box 227:, Folder 1287)
    - Pioneers in Industry, 1945 (Box 227:, Folder 1288)
    - “Sidelights on Brass Mill History”, 1952 (Box 227:, Folder 1289)
    - Tercentenary Pictorial and History of the Lower Naugatuck Valley, 1935 (Box 227:, Folder 1290)
    - Testimonial Album from American Industry to Soviet Industry, 1942; (1 volume) (Box 228:, Folder 1291)
- Series XI: Publications, 1940-1988
  - A Story of Selected Markets in Brazil (Box 229:, Folder 1292)
  - Africa I (Box 229:, Folder 1293)
  - Annual Reports, 1946 (Box 229:, Folder 1294)
  - Annual Reports, 1964, 1967 (Box 229:, Folder 1295)
  - Annual Reports, 1974 (Box 229:, Folder 1296)
  - Boston Rubber Group Address, 1976 (Box 229:, Folder 1297)
  - Branford & Electric Railway Journal, 1987 (Box 229:, Folder 1298)
  - Casting Engineering, 1980 (Box 229:, Folder 1299)
  - Catalogs (Box 229:, Folder 1300)
  - Catalog: Machinery (Box 229:, Folder 1301)
  - Centennial, 1848-1948 (Box 229:, Folder 1302)
  - Competitiveness, 1964 (Box 229:, Folder 1303)
  - Computers, 1973 (Box 229:, Folder 1304)
  - Connecticut Industry, 1966 Sept (Box 229:, Folder 1305)
  - Continuous Mixer Manual, 1964 (Box 229:, Folder 1306)
  - Development of Workers' Compensation in Connecticut, 1987 (Box 229:, Folder 1307)
  - “E” Award, 1966 (Box 229:, Folder 1308)
  - East European Market, 1972 (Box 229:, Folder 1309)
  - Emhart - Stockholders' Reports (Box 229:, Folder 1310)
  - Emhart Annual Report, 1984-1988 (Box 229:, Folder 1311)
  - Emhart News (Box 229:, Folder 1312)
  - Energy: Conservation in the Rubber Industry, 1978 (Box 229:, Folder 1313)
  - Equipment (Box 229:, Folder 1314)
  - Equipment News (Box 229:, Folder 1315)
  - Europe East I (Box 229:, Folder 1316)
  - Europe East II (Box 229:, Folder 1317)
  - F-B Notes, 1940-1944 (Box 229:, Folder 1318)
  - F-B Notes, 1945-1946 (Box 229:, Folder 1319)
  - Flood Report, 1955 (Box 230:, Folder 1320)
  - History of Company (Box 230:, Folder 1321)
  - International News (Box 230:, Folder 1322)
  - International Sales Seminar, 1975 (Box 230:, Folder 1323)
  - Italian Mechanical Assoc. Address (Box 230:, Folder 1324)
  - Machine Blueprints: boring, drilling, milling (Box 230:, Folder 1325)
  - Manufacturing Facilities, CT, 1976 (Box 230:, Folder 1326)
  - Middle East (Box 230:, Folder 1327)
  - Newsletter (Box 230:, Folder 1328)
  - Newspaper clippings (Box 230:, Folder 1329)
  - Old Timer's Club - Christmas Program, 1985 (Box 230:, Folder 1330)
  - Open House, 1981 (Box 230:, Folder 1331)
  - Organization Charts, 1982 (Box 230:, Folder 1332)
  - Pomini/Farrel (Box 230:, Folder 1333-1334)
  - Procedures Review and Study of Ansonia (Box 230:, Folder 1335)
  - Product Information (Box 230:, Folder 1336-1339)
  - Products (Box 230:, Folder 1340)
  - Profit Making Ideas for Industry, 1963 (Box 230:, Folder 1341)
  - Railroad Equipment International Sales, 1975 (Box 230:, Folder 1342)
  - Report on Visit to Middle East, 1975 (Box 230:, Folder 1343)
  - Report to Advisory Board, 1972 (Box 230:, Folder 1344)
  - Reports (Box 230:, Folder 1345)
  - Research and Development Report (Box 230:, Folder 1346)
  - Roll Grinders Listing, 1977 (Box 230:, Folder 1347)
  - Roll Grinders Listing, 1970 (Box 231:, Folder 1348)
  - Rubber and Plastics Market, 1980s (Box 231:, Folder 1349)
  - Rubber Mixing (Box 231:, Folder 1350)
  - Sales Conference, 1961 (Box 231:, Folder 1351)
  - Sales Engineering Data Sheets (Box 231:, Folder 1352)
  - Solid Men of the Place: Farrel, Franklin & Almon, 1956 (Box 231:, Folder 1353)
  - Sugar Machinery Instructional Manual, 1979 (Box 231:, Folder 1354)
  - Sugar Mill (Box 231:, Folder 1355)
  - Supervisors Policy (Box 231:, Folder 1356)
  - USM Corporation (Box 232:, Folder 1357)
  - USM Policy and Procedures (Box 232:, Folder 1358)
  - USM Today, 1968 August - 1970 September (Box 232:, Folder 1359)
  - USM Today, 1970, 1975-1976 (Box 232:, Folder 1360)
  - Wealth, Taxation and Fiscal Policy, 1972 (Box 232:, Folder 1361)
- Series XII: Addendum, 1800-1989
  - Subject Files
    - Beaver Pond Brook (Box 233:, Folder 1362)
    - Casting Chilled Rolls, 1871 (Box 233:, Folder 1363-1364)
    - Connecticut Industry and Italian Independence: Parrela, 1870 (Box 233:, Folder 1365)
    - Cost control/pricing, 1956 (Box 233:, Folder 1366)
    - Emhart/Black & Decker merger, 1989 (Box 233:, Folder 1367)
    - Emhart/Farrel lawsuit, 1987 (Box 233:, Folder 1368)
    - Emhart takeover, 1989 (Box 233:, Folder 1369)
    - Franklin Farrel Jr., correspondence, oral history (Box 233:, Folder 1370)
    - Franklin Farrel III, correspondence (Box 233:, Folder 1371)
    - Franklin Farrel III, reminiscences (Box 233:, Folder 1372)
    - Flood emergency procedures (Box 233:, Folder 1373)
    - Fulling Mill Brook (Box 233:, Folder 1374)
    - Health Benefit plan, 1983 (Box 233:, Folder 1375)
    - Invitations, announcements, certificates (Box 233:, Folder 1376)
    - Kelly, Hugh (Box 233:, Folder 1377)
    - Legal records, 1800-1900 (Box 233:, Folder 1378)
    - Liberty Amendment Committee (Box 233:, Folder 1379)
    - Miner & Peck products, 1930 (Box 233:, Folder 1380)
    - Patent (Box 233:, Folder 1381)
    - Personnel, executive signatures (Box 233:, Folder 1382)
    - Production improvements, 1912-1913 (Box 233:, Folder 1383)
    - Production report, 1947 (Box 233:, Folder 1384)
    - Public Relations correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 233:, Folder 1385)
    - Public Relations - news releases, 1944-1945 (Box 233:, Folder 1386)
    - Public Relations - personnel publicity (Box 233:, Folder 1387)
    - Public Relations - promotional items (Box 233:, Folder 1388)
    - Stock holders/transactions, 1940-1968 (Box 233:, Folder 1389)
    - Trolley tales (Box 233:, Folder 1390)
    - Unionmelt Experiment report, 1943 (Box 233:, Folder 1391)
    - WWI bond drives (Box 233:, Folder 1392)
- Series XIII: Ledgers
  - Cash Book, 1923-1923 (Box 234:, Folder 1393)
  - Miscellaneous Ledgers (Box 235-260:, Folder 1394-1419)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1866-1874 (Box 261:, Folder 1420)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1885-1887 (Volume 262:, Othertype 1421)
  - Accounts Ledger “I”, 1888 (Volume 263:, Othertype 1422)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1889-1891 (Volume 264:, Othertype 1423)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1892-1896 (Volume 265:, Othertype 1424)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1897-1899 (Volume 266:, Othertype 1425)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1900-1903 (Volume 267:, Othertype 1426)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1903-1905 (Volume 268:, Othertype 1427)
  - Accounts Ledger, 1907-1912 (Volume 269:, Othertype 1428)
  - Journal, 1884-1887 (Volume 270:, Othertype 1429)
  - Journal, 1888-1893 (Volume 271:, Othertype 1430)
  - Journal, 1893-1900 (Volume 272:, Othertype 1431)
  - Journal, 1900-1906 (Volume 273:, Othertype 1432)
  - Journal, 1906-1914 (Volume 274:, Othertype 1433)
  - Invoice Journal, 1914-1920 (Volume 275:, Othertype 1434)
  - Invoice Journal, 1887-1890 (Volume 276:, Othertype 1435)
  - Invoice Journal, 1890-1895 (Volume 277:, Othertype 1436)
  - Invoice Journal, 1895-1903 (Volume 278:, Othertype 1437)
  - Miscellaneous Ledger, 1917-1919 (Volume 279:, Othertype 1438)
  - Indexes (Volume 280:, Othertype 1439)
  - Timebook, 1891-1892 (Volume 281:, Othertype 1440)
  - Payroll Recap, 1929-1934 (Volume 282:, Othertype 1441)
  - Payroll Recap, 1938-1942 (Volume 283:, Othertype 1442)
  - General Account Summary, 1920-1925 (Volume 284:, Othertype 1443)
  - General Account Summary, 1925-1927 (Volume 285:, Othertype 1444)
  - General Account Summary, 1929-1930 (Volume 286:, Othertype 1445)
  - General Account Summary, 1931-1935 (Volume 287:, Othertype 1446)
  - Quote book, undated (Volume 288:, Othertype 1447)
  - Account Summary, 1925-1929 (Volume 289:, Othertype 1448)
  - Accounts Receivable and Paid, 1920-1923 (Volume 290:, Othertype 1449)
  - Accounts Receivable and Paid, 1926-1930 (Volume 291:, Othertype 1450)
  - Accounts Receivable and Paid, 1930-1935 (Volume 292:, Othertype 1451)
  - Accounts Payable, 1912-1920 (Volume 293:, Othertype 1452)
  - Accounts Payable, 1920-1925 (Volume 294:, Othertype 1453)
  - Accounts Receivable - A - M, 1912-1920 (Volume 295:, Othertype 1454)
  - Accounts Receivable - N - Z, 1912-1920 (Volume 296:, Othertype 1455)
  - Accounts Receivable - I - R, 1920-1925 (Volume 297:, Othertype 1456)
  - Accounts Receivable - S - Z, 1920-1925 (Volume 298:, Othertype 1457)
  - Accounts Receivable - A - L, 1925-1929 (Volume 299:, Othertype 1458)
  - Accounts Receivable - M - Z, 1925-1929 (Volume 300:, Othertype 1459)
  - Order Book, 1930s (Volume 301:, Othertype 1460)
  - Auditing Information, 1926-1927 (Volume 302:, Othertype 1461)
- Series XIV: Photographs, undated
  - Ansonia Photographs 54-519 (Othertype 1:, Othertype 1)
  - Ansonia Photographs 520-879 (Othertype 2:, Othertype 2)
  - Ansonia Photographs 880-1289 (Othertype 3:, Othertype 3)
  - Ansonia Photographs 1290-1579 (Othertype 4:, Othertype 4)
  - Ansonia Photographs 1580-1915 (Othertype 5:, Othertype 5)
  - Ansonia Photographs 1916-2100 (Othertype 6:, Othertype 6)
  - Derby Photographs 99-1599 (Othertype 6:, Othertype 7)
  - Derby Photographs 1600-1819 (Othertype 7:, Othertype 8)
  - Derby Photographs 1820-2065 (Othertype 8:, Othertype 9)
  - Prints from Publisher's Photo Service, Stamford (Othertype 9:, Othertype 10)
  - Derby Retouches (Othertype 10:, Othertype 11)
  - Derby Retouches (Othertype 11:, Othertype 12)
  - Derby Retouches (Othertype 12:, Othertype 13)
  - Derby Negatives (Othertype 13:, Othertype 14)
  - Derby Negatives (Othertype 14:, Othertype 15)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 15:, Othertype 16)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 16:, Othertype 17)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 17:, Othertype 18)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 18:, Othertype 19)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 19:, Othertype 20)
  - Buffalo (Othertype 20:, Othertype 21)
- Series XV: 2012 accession, 1923-1993; 4.0 Linear feet
  - Scrapbooks of photographs of the Pomini, Italy, plant dedication (1967); worker retirement parties, damage to the Connecticut plant from the Flood of 1955; Franklin Farrel 3rd being honored by Junior Achievement of Western Connecticut (1980); notes, intineraries and reports of business trips taken by FF3 to Venezuela and Argentina (1972); copies of The Farrel Buffaolonian (mock company newsletter); transcript and film of reminiscenses of Franklin Farrel Jr. (1966); documents and correspondence about history of the Farrel family; official citation from the mayor of Ansonia, Connecticut, in appreciation of the contributions of FF3 and the Farrel family; publications, newsclippings and reports about Flood of 1955, photographs from the Farrel "Old Timer's Club" (1960s), 1955-1980 (Box 2012-0130_1)
  - Brochures from the Farrel Company's 75th anniversary (1923), Centennial Celebration brochure (1948); catalogs and brochures about company and its products; company telephone directory (1975), Ansonia, Connecticut, plant drawings; company financial information (1985), 1923-1985 (Box 2012-0130_2)
  - USM Corporation Farrell Division site plans (1975 and 1985), poster with photographs of mayors of Ansonia, Connecticut, 1975, 1985, 1993 (Roll 2012-0130_3)
- Appendix A: Company Name Changes, 1848-1983
  - Almon Farrel and Company, 1848
  - Farrel-Johnson Company, 1849
  - Farrel Foundry, 1950
  - Farrel Foundry and Machine Company, 1857
  - Farrel-Birmingham Comopany, Inc., 1927
  - Farrel Corporation, 1963
  - Farrel Machinery Group, 1976
  - The Farrel Comopany, Emhart Machinery Group, 1983
- Appendix B: Presidents of the Farrel Company, 1848-1983
  - Almon Farrel, 1848-1957
  - Joshua M. Colburn, 1857-1862
  - Sullivan Colburn, 1862-1866
  - David Plumb, 1866-1867
  - J.H. Bartholomew, 1867-1869
  - Franklin Farrel, 1869-1912
  - Charles F. Bliss, 1912-1928
  - Walter Perry, 1828-1930
  - Nelson W. Pickering, 1930-1943
  - John Haddock, 1943-1945
  - Franklin Hoadley, 1945-1955
  - Franklin Farrel, 3rd, 1955-1973
  - Bernard Didsbury, 1973-1980
  - Kenneth Josephson, 1980-1983
  - Jan Tomczycki, 1983-